Hi, I'm Peter Navarro and I'll be your professor for
مرحبا، أنا بيتر نافارو وسأكون أستاذ الخاص بك
this course on managing your time, money and career.
لهذه الدورة في إدارة وقتك والمال والمهنية.
I've been a professor at UC Irvine business school here in Sunny California,
لقد كنت أستاذاً في جامعة كاليفورنيا إيرفين في كلية إدارة الأعمال هنا في صني كاليفورنيا
for over 25 years, and I'm delighted to be able to share with you some
، لأكثر من 25 عاماً، ويسعدني أن أكون قادراً على مشاركتكم بعض
insights about personal finance and management.
الأفكار حول التمويل الشخصي والإدارة.
Usually reserve for my MBA students.
عادة ما يحجز لطلاب الماجستير في إدارة الأعمال.
>> And I'm Alex LeBon.
>> وأنا اليكس Lebon.
I'm an undergraduate student majoring in physics that experienced firsthand
أنا طالب جامعي متخصص في الفيزياء التي شهدت مباشرة
most of the issues and problems we're going to be talking about in this course.
معظم القضايا والمشاكل التي سنتحدث عنها في هذه الدورة.
You will be seeing and hearing me throughout the video lessons, and
سوف تراني وتسمعني طوال دروس الفيديو،
I will be helping explain and translate the business and
وسأساعد في شرح وترجم
economics concepts from Professor Navarro to your everyday lives as a student.
مفاهيم الأعمال والاقتصاد من البروفيسور نافارو إلى حياتك اليومية كطالب.
>> Here then is the deal.
>> هنا ثم هو الصفقة.
This course is designed to be both practical and fun.
تم تصميم هذه الدورة لتكون عملية وممتعة على حد سواء.
And it should be a very low stress experience.
وينبغي أن تكون تجربة الإجهاد منخفضة جدا.
>> If you simply view the online lectures a couple of times, take the quizzes,
>> إذا كنت ببساطة عرض المحاضرات على الانترنت بضع مرات, اتخاذ مسابقات,
You should get a very high rate of return on this educational investment.
يجب أن تحصل على نسبة عالية جدا من العائد على هذا الاستثمار التعليمي.
>> As for the topics you will be studying, they range from budgeting, borrowing and
>> أما بالنسبة للمواضيع التي ستدرسها، فهي تتراوح بين الميزنة والاقتراض
credit score management to saving and
وإدارة درجة الائتمان إلى الادخار
investing, insurance, taxes and even entrepreneurship.
والاستثمار والتأمين والضرائب وحتى ريادة الأعمال.
>> And one note about the content.
>> وملاحظة واحدة حول المحتوى.
In most of your classes, the lessons will be structured in a clear progression where
في معظم الفصول الدراسية الخاصة بك، سيتم تنظيم الدروس في تطور واضح حيث
each lesson builds on the next as the material becomes more and more difficult.
يبني كل درس على التالي عندما تصبح المادة أكثر وأكثر صعوبة.
But that's not what we will be doing here.
لكن هذا ليس ما سنفعله هنا
>> That's right, Alex.
>> هذا صحيح، اليكس.
Each of the lessons in this class more or less stand on their own.
كل من الدروس في هذه الفئة أكثر أو أقل تقف من تلقاء نفسها.
But they are also highly related to at least some of the other lessons,
ولكنها ترتبط أيضا ارتباطا وثيقا ببعض الدروس الأخرى على الأقل،
as if in a web.
كما لو كان في شبكة الإنترنت.
>> For example,
>> على سبيل المثال،
in one lesson we'll teach the concept of having a plan for your money.
في درس واحد سوف نعلّم مفهوم وجود خطة لأموالك.
But in other lessons we will show you related concepts like
ولكن في دروس أخرى سوف نعرض لك المفاهيم ذات الصلة مثل
investment strategies and credit.
استراتيجيات الاستثمار والائتمان.
>> So keep that in mind while you're going through the lessons, and
>> لذلك ضع ذلك في اعتبارك أثناء الخوض في الدروس،
don't be afraid to go back to lessons to keep your knowledge fresh
ولا تخف من العودة إلى الدروس للحفاظ على معرفتك جديدة
when we reference a particular subject outside of it's lesson.
عندما نشير إلى موضوع معين خارج الدرس.
>> And here's my first key tip for you.
>> وهنا أول نصيحة رئيسية بالنسبة لك.
One of the most powerful things about a Coursera course
واحدة من أقوى الأشياء في دورة Coursera
is the community discussion forums.
هي منتديات النقاش المجتمعي.
>> That's right, be sure to post your questions, personal insights or
>> هذا صحيح، تأكد من نشر أسئلتك، الرؤى الشخصية أو
additional related resources.
الموارد الإضافية ذات الصلة.
While Alex and I cannot answer all of your questions,
بينما أنا و (أليكسس) لا نستطيع الإجابة على جميع أسئلتك،
the vast community of learners in the course can help fill that gap.
يمكن للمجتمع الواسع من المتعلمين في الدورة أن يساعدوا في سد تلك الفجوة.
And you will benefit greatly from the collective insights
وسوف تستفيد كثيرا من الرؤى الجماعية
of your fellow students.
لزملائك الطلاب.
>> So now, let's get ready for what should be a very interesting ride.
>> حتى الآن، دعونا نستعد لما ينبغي أن يكون ركوب مثيرة جدا للاهتمام.
Jump right into the first lesson, and enjoy the course.
القفز الحق في الدرس الأول، والتمتع الدورة.
[BLANK AUDIO]
[ صوت فارغ]